Sculpture Medium Format Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Sculpture Medium Format Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 13
Yale University Arts Library
31.6
20 boxes
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of sculpture. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by country. Further subdivided by individual artist name.
Scope and Contents
Collection consists of mounted black and white and color reproductions of sculpture. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Sculpture; Photographs; Reproductions
- Egypt
  - Miscellaneous works., 14 (Box 1)
- Mesopotamia
  - Miscellaneous works., 6 (Box 1)
- Aegean
  - Miscellaneous works., 5 (Box 1)
- Persia
  - Miscellaneous works., 2 (Box 1)
- Syria
  - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 1)
- Greece
  - Archaic Period and date not known., 7 (Box 2)
  - Transitional Period., 13 (Box 2)
  - Great Period., 23 (Box 3)
  - Hellenistic Period., 19 (Box 4)
- Roman
  - Miscellaneous works., 21 (Box 5)
- Early Medieval.
  - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 5)
- Austria
  - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 6)
- Britain.
  - Anonymous Artists., 2 (Box 6)
  - Known Artists., 7
    - Epstein, Jacob, 1880-1959., 1 (Box 6)
    - Gill, Eric, 1882-1940., 2 (Box 6)
    - Moore, Henry, 1898-1986., 2 (Box 6)
    - Roubillac, Louis Francis, 1695-1762., 1 (Box 6)
    - Stevens, Alfred, 1823-1906., 1 (Box 6)
- Denmark
  - Known Artists., 2
    - Fluur, Nils, active c.1684-1689., 1 (Box 6)
    - Thorwaldsen, Bertel, 1770-1844., 1 (Box 6)
- Flanders
  - Known Artists., 2
    - Duquesnoy, Jerome the Elder, 1570-1641., 1 (Box 6)
    - Massys, Jan, 1509-1575., 1 (Box 6)
- France
  - Anonymous Artists., 21
    - XII Century., 6 (Box 7)
    - XIII Century., 6 (Box 7)
    - XIV Century., 3 (Box 7)
    - XV Century., 6 (Box 7)
  - Known Artists., 65
    - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 14
      - Bouchardon, Edme, 1698-1761., 1 (Box 8)
      - Colombe, Michel, School of, c.1523., 1 (Box 8)
      - Despiau, Charles, 1874-1946., 1 (Box 8)
      - Duchamp-Villon, Raymond, 1876-1918., 1 (Box 8)
      - Fresnaye, Roger de la, 1885-1925., 1 (Box 8)
      - Girardon, Francois, 1628-1715., 1 (Box 8)
      - Laurens, Henri, 1885-1954., 1 (Box 8)
      - Leger, Fernand, 1881-1955., 1 (Box 8)
      - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973., 2 (Box 8)
      - Mallot, G., Workshop of, Renaissance., 1 (Box 8)
      - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954., 1 (Box 8)
      - Richier, Ligier, 1500-1567/72., 1 (Box 8)
      - Rude, Francois, 1784-1855., 1 (Box 8)
    - Individual Artists., 51
      - Arp, Hans, 1888-1966., 3 (Box 8)
      - Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968., 2 (Box 8)
      - Maillol, Aristide, 1861-1944., 16 (Box 8)
      - Pilon, Germain, 1535--1590., 3 (Box 9)
      - Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917., 17 (Box 9)
      - Sluter, Claus, -1405., 6 (Box 9)
- Germany
  - Anonymous Artists., 6
    - XVI Century., 6 (Box 10)
  - Known Artists, A-Z., 7
    - Appel, Karel, 1921-., 1 (Box 10)
    - Barlach, Ernst, 1870-1938., 1 (Box 10)
    - Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, 1881-1919., 1 (Box 10)
    - Leinberger, Hans, c.1480-1536/7., 1 (Box 10)
    - Marcks, Gerhard, 1889-1981., 1 (Box 10)
    - Stoss, Veit, 1447-1542., 2 (Box 10)
- Italy
  - Anonymous Artists., 11
    - Byzantine., 1 (Box 11)
    - XV Century., 8 (Box 11)
      Scope and Contents
      Some of these are marked as fake.
    - XVI Century., 2 (Box 11)
  - Known Artists., 195
    - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 19
      - Agostino di Giovanni, 1269-1348., 1 (Box 11)
      - Amadeo, Giovanni A., 1477-1522., 1 (Box 11)
      - Boccioni, Umberto, 1882-1916., 1 (Box 11)
      - Conti, Niccolo dei, active 1556-1574., 1 (Box 11)
      - Dalle Massegne, P. and J., active 1383-1409., 1 (Box 11)
      - Desiderio da Settignano, c.1430-1464., 1 (Box 11)
      - Gai, Antonio, 1686-1769., 1 (Box 11)
      - Lombardo, Tullio, 1455-1532., 1 (Box 11)
      - Manzu, Giacomo, 1908-., 1 (Box 11)
      - Marini, Marino, 1901-1980., 1 (Box 11)
      - Mino da Fiesole, Manner of, XV C., 1 (Box 11)
      - Montauti, Antonio, -c.1740., 1 (Box 11)
      - Orcagna, Andrea, active 1343- died 1368., 1 (Box 11)
      - Pisano, Andrea, c.1290-c.1348., 1 (Box 11)
      - Pisano, Giovanni, c.1245-c.1314., 1 (Box 11)
      - Ricciarelli, 1509-1566., 2 (Box 11)
        Also known as Daniele da Volterra.
      - Rossellino, Antonio, 1427-1479., 1 (Box 11)
      - Tino da Camaino, c.1285-1337., 1 (Box 11)
      - Zandomeneghi, Luigi and Pietro, XIX C., 1 (Box 11)
    - Individual Artists, A-Z., 176
      - Baldini, Giacomello, XVI C., 1 (Box 12)
      - Banco, Nanni di, c.1383-1471., 2 (Box 12)
      - Benedetto da Maiano, 1442-1497., 3 (Box 12)
      - Bernini, Giovanni Lorenzo, 1598-1680., 4 (Box 12)
      - Canova, Antonio, 1757-1822., 3 (Box 12)
      - Cellini, Benvenuto, 1500-1571., 2 (Box 12)
      - Donatello, 1386-1466., 9 (Box 12)
      - Dupre, Giovanni, 1817-1882., 2 (Box 12)
      - Ghiberti, Lorenzo, 1378-1455., 9 (Box 12)
      - Giovanni da Bologna, 1524-1608., 5 (Box 13)
      - Leopardi, Alessandro, -1522., 3 (Box 13)
      - Michelangelo, Buonarrotti, 1475-1564., 120
        - Miscellaneous locations., 5 (Box 13)
        - Bologna., 4 (Box 13)
        - Bruges., 5 (Box 13)
        - Florence., 79
          - Miscellaneous works., 21 (Box 14)
          - Bacchus., 4 (Box 15)
          - Boboli Captives., 4 (Box 15)
          - Brutus., 4 (Box 15)
          - David., 7 (Box 15)
          - Dejanira Relief., 4 (Box 15)
          - Medici Tomb., 30
            - Tomb of Giuliano de'Medici., 17 (Box 16)
            - Tomb of Lorenzo de'Medici., 13 (Box 16)
          - The Victory., 5 (Box 17)
        - Leningrad/St. Petersburg., 2 (Box 17)
        - London., 1 (Box 17)
        - Paris., 7 (Box 17)
        - Rome., 17 (Box 17)
      - Robbia, Luca della, 1399-1482, and Andrea della, 1435-1525., 7 (Box 18)
      - Sansovino, Andrea, 1460-1529., 2 (Box 18)
      - Verrochio, Andrea del, 1436-1488., 4 (Box 18)
- Rumania.
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 1
    - Brancusi, Constantin, 1876-1957., 1 (Box 19)
- Russia.
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 3
    - Archipenko, Alexander, 1887-1964., 1 (Box 19)
    - Gabo, Naum, 1890-1977., 1 (Box 19)
    - Pevsner, Antoine, 1886-1962., 1 (Box 19)
- Spain.
  - Anonymous Artists., 4
    - XVI Century., 4 (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 6
    - Berruguete, Alonso, 1489-1566., 1 (Box 19)
    - Cano, Alonzo, 1601-1667., 1 (Box 19)
    - Giratte, Francisco, attributed to, ?., 1 (Box 19)
    - Juni, Juan de, c.1507-1577., 1 (Box 19)
    - Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973., 1 (Box 19)
    - Velasquez, Diego, statue after, 1599-1660., 1 (Box 19)
- Switzerland.
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 1
    - Giacometti, Alberto, 1901-1966., 1 (Box 19)
- Latin America.
  - Miscellaneous Artists, A-Z., 6
    - Rafael, Jesus, 1923-., 1 (Box 19)
    - Tolsa, Manuel, 1757-1816., 5 (Box 19)
- United States.
  - Anonymous Artists., 9 (Box 20)
  - Known Artists., 27
    - Miscellaneous Artists., 17
      - Bartlett, Paul W., 1865-., 1 (Box 20)
      - Ben-Shmuel, Ahron, 1903-., 1 (Box 20)
      - Borglum, Gutzon, 1867-1941., 3 (Box 20)
      - Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976., 1 (Box 20)
      - Flannagan, John B., 1898-1942., 1 (Box 20)
      - Jennewein, C. Paul, 1890-1978., 1 (Box 20)
      - Lachaise, Gaston, 1882-1935., 2 (Box 20)
      - Meizer, Michael, 1944-., 1 (Box 20)
      - McCartan, Edward, 1879-1947., 1 (Box 20)
        Work done with Rene Chambellan.
      - Quinn, Edmond, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 20)
      - Thompson, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 20)
      - Zorach, William, 1887-1966., 2 (Box 20)
    - Individual Artists, A-Z., 10
      - French, Daniel Chester, 1850-1931., 2 (Box 20)
      - Palmer, Erastus D., 1817-1904., 6 (Box 20)
        Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Smith, David, 1906-1965., 2 (Box 20)